SAYAN MOULICK

Kolkata, WB 700034 • smoulickn@gmail.com • (+91) 9230008980 • https://sayanmoulick.github.io/

SUMMARY

QA engineer with 4 years of experience in manual and automation testing. Skilled in creating test plans, test suite, test cases scripts, identifying defects, and using modern testing tools and methodologies to enhance software performance and reliability.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tier5 Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Kolkata, WB Quality Analyst

February - August 2024

- Using manual and automation testing, identified 250+ defects in existing build.
- Test Planning, Test case preparation, execution of test suites helped to identify and reduce more than 95% errors in just 7 months.
- Performed smoke testing, regression testing, sanity testing.
- Functional testings including UI testing, API testing, database testing. Also Non functional testing like load and security testing.
- In SDLC worked closely with developers from backend, frontend to mitigate the errors before releases. Shared daily work statuses on scrum meeting.

May 2021 - June 2023

- Neosoft Technologies., Mumbai, MH Software Engineer
- Served as outsourced resource to clients of Neosoft.
- Test Planning, Test case preparation, execution of test suites identified 98% errors before releases helped sales team to achive all time high product sell benchmark in this 2 year period.
- Performed smoke testing, regression testing, sanity testing.
- Functional testings including UI testing, API testing, database testing. Also Non functional testing like load and security testing.
- Worked closely with developers from backend, frontend to mitigate the errors before releases. Shared daily work statuses on scrum meeting.

July 2019-October 2020

- ThirdEye Data Analytics Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata, WB Junior Data Engineer
- UI/UX Testing, API testing, database testing.
- Manual testing of NLP based chatbots and their dashboard portal.
- Training of client chatbots as per their requirements.
- Data annotations

SKILLS

• UI/UX Testing : Selenium Java, TestNG, Selenium Python, Cypress Javascript

• BDD frameworks : Cucumber, Behave

API Testing : Postman, Jmeter, SoapUI

Database Testing : MySQL, MongoDB

• SCM Version Control: Git

• CI/CD : Jenkins

Miscellaneous : Attention to detail, Communication, Team coordination, Learn new things

EDUCATION

•	Pondicherry University, Puducherry Master of Computer Applications, CGPA: 8.7/10	2016 - 2019
•	Asutosh College, University of Calcutta, Kolkata Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Honors : Percentatge 68%	2013 - 2016
•	Higher Secondary / 12th, WBCHSE, Kolkata Percentatge 70%	2013
•	Secondary / 10th, WBBSE, Kolkata Percentatge 70%	2011

COURSES

1. Live Apps Performance Testing using JMETER	UDEMY	#UC-ee129c3c-25cd-4e60-8273-0cff190bd6d9
2. Webservices - SOAP / REST API Testing	UDEMY	#UC-838905e9-ec2c-4a9c-b051-771b2a74ddea
3. Cypress Modern Automation Testing	UDEMY	#UC-10a39d02-57b1-40c6-bba2-ffb0e1e3c145
4. Jenkins Master DevOps	UDEMY	#UC-30d9aad5-a630-4fe4-ba71-c4d41c694141
5. Advanced NodeJs	LinkedIn	#AW5fiTXCMc2iyVUYMe1D_7w3DqjG

CERTIFICATIONS

1. Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC™) SCRUMstudy #958103